Guide to the Douglass Cecil North Papers, 1942-2012 and undated RL.00955
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Douglass Cecil North papers
1942-2012 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
North, Douglass Cecil
RL.00955
50 Linear Feet
Economist and faculty member of Washington University in Saint Louis, Mo., and winner of the Nobel Prize in Economics in 1993. The papers of Douglass C. North date from 1942-2012 and consist chiefly of professional correspondence written and received by North, writings by North and other colleagues (the largest group), and files on conferences attended by North; there are also some teaching materials. The collection documents North's career as an economist and professor at Berkeley, University of Washington, Rice University, and Washington University (Missouri), and reflects his interests in economics, the economic history of the western world, transaction costs, economic development, institutional change, and industrialization and technology. Among the correspondents are many noted economists, including Yoram Barzel, Robert Bates, Reuven Brenner, Robert Clower, R. H. Coase, Robert Fogel, Robert Haveman, Robert Keohane, Simon Kuznets, Deirdre N. McCloskey, Elinor Ostrom, Vernon Smith, T. N. Srinivasan, John J. Wallis, and Barry R. Weingast.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Douglass Cecil North Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1993, 2000, 2008, and 2013.
Biographical Note
Missing Title
1920 Born in Cambridge, Massachusetts
1941 Worked for one summer with Dorothea Lange, photographer; her husband, in Economics Department at the University of California, convinced North to study economics
1942 Received B.A. from University of California, Berkeley
1942-1946 Served in the U.S. Merchant Marines
1950-1979 Professor at University of Washington
1952 Received Ph.D. from University of California, Berkeley
1956-1957 Research Associate at the National Bureau of Economic Research; his major quantitative study of the balance of payments of the United States from 1790 to 1860 led to publication of first book in 1961
1960-1966 Co-editor of the Journal of Economic History
1961 Publication of book, The Economic Growth of the United States, 1790 to 1860
1961-present Director, Institute of Economic Research at Washington University
1966 Publication of book, Growth and Welfare in the American Past: A New Economic History
1966-1967 Became interested in European economic history and spent the year in Geneva as a Ford Faculty Fellow
1971 Publication of book, Institutional Change and American Economic Growth (with L. E. Davis)
1972 Elected President of the Economic History Association
1973 Publication of The Rise of the Western World: A New Economic History (with R. P. Thomas) Visiting Director of the Centre de Recherche Historique at the Ecole Pratique des Hautes Etudes, Paris
1979 Professor, Rice University
1981 Publication of book, Structure and Change in Economic History
1981-1982 Professor, University of Cambridge, England
1983 Moved to Washington University in St. Louis, where he created the Center in Political Economy
1990 Publication of book, Institutions, Institutional Change, and Economic Performance
1993 Awarded Nobel Memorial Prize in Economics (jointly with Robert W. Fogel)
1996 Elected as Fellow of the British Academy
1997 Advisor, World Development Report 1997: The State in a Changing World, the World Bank
2003 Awarded Honorary Degree, Doctor of Humanities, Washington University, St. Louis, Missouri
2005 Publication of the book, Understanding the Process of Economic Change
2009 Publication of the book, Violence and Social Orders: A Conceptual Framework for Interpreting Recorded Human History (with John J. Wallis and Barry R. Weingast)
2012 Publication of the book, In the Shadow of Violence: Politics, Economics, and the Problems of Development (with John J. Wallis, Steven B. Webb and Barry R. Weingast)
2015 Died, Benzonia, Michigan.
Collection Overview
The papers of university professor and Nobel Prize-winning economist Douglass C. North span the dates 1942-2012, with most of the papers being dated between 1970 and 2012. They consist chiefly of professional correspondence written and received by North, writings by North and other colleagues, and files on conferences attended by North. There are also materials relating to courses he taught. The collection documents North's career as an economist and professor at Berkeley, University of Washington, Rice University, and Washington University (Missouri), and reflects his interests in economics, the economic history of the western world, transaction costs, economic development, institutional change, and industrialization and technology. More specifically, the papers document his long-standing interest in explaining institutional change and political economies without relying exclusively on neo-classical economic theories. His political economy draw him closer to approaches of classical political economy.
Among the correspondents are many noted economists, including Yoram Barzel, Robert Bates, Reuven Brenner, Robert Clower, R.H. Coase, Robert Fogel, Robert Haveman, Robert Keohane, Simon Kuznets, Deirdre N. McCloskey, Emily Chamlee-Wright, Elinor Ostrom, Vernon Smith, T.N. Srinivasan, John J. Wallis and Barry R. Weingast. Some of these correspondents are also represented in the Writings Series of this collection, a large group which contains drafts, notes, and reprints of writings by North as well as writings by his colleagues.
North's secretary Fannie Batt is an important factor for a proper understanding of the nature of this collection. After receiving the Nobel Prize in 1993, North's correspondence expanded substantially. Fannie Batt, his secretary at the Washington University in St. Louis, was tasked to take care of the correspondence for North. Her role impacted the subsequent arrangement of the collection. Materials are often Fannie Batt's printouts of correspondence for North. Most of the correspondence since the 1990s is carried through Fannie Batt's email address. Also, North's own responses to emails are not as frequent in the collection as one would expect. Existing responses were often dictated by North and typed by Fannie Batt.
Economic development; Economics -- Methodology; Economic history; Economic history -- Congresses; Transaction costs; Keynesian economics; International economic relations; Institutional analysis; Industrialization; Economists -- Correspondence; Economics -- Study and teaching; Srinivasan, T. N., 1933-; Smith, Vernon L.; Ostrom, Elinor; North, Douglass Cecil; Washington University (Saint Louis, Mo.) -- Faculty; Haveman, Robert H.; Fogel, Robert William; Coase, R. H. (Ronald Harry); Clower, Robert W.; McCloskey, Deirdre N.; Kuznets, Simon Smith, 1901-; Keohane, Robert O. (Robert Owen), 1941-; Bates, Robert H.; Brenner, Reuven; Barzel, Yoram; Batt, Fannie
- Professional Correspondence, 1950-2012; 1
  Scope and Contents
  Series consists of incoming and some outgoing correspondence spanning many decades, and is organized chronologically. Note fields for most entries highlight significant correspondents or topics. The early correspondence (1950s to 1980) contains mainly departmental correspondence, proposals, conference invitations, and research exchanges, especially with departmental colleague and collaborator Morris David Morris at the University of Washington. From the 1980s on, files chiefly contain recommendation letters, academic appointments, invitations, workshops, proposals, and reports as well as other routine academic correspondence. In some cases, manuscripts of book chapters, papers or abstracts are attached to correspondence. Prominent correspondents include Robert Fogel, Amartya Sen, Vernon Smith, Elinor Ostrom, George Stigler, Oliver E. Williamson and Herman Wold. Note that since 1990s, D. North's correspondence was mainly conducted by his secretary, Fannie Batt. This series contain files called "Stanford" and "Benzonia". Those files and some others are preserved as received by Rubenstein. They contain correspondence forwarded by fax to North by his secretary. Since 1990s, North used to spend summers in Benzonia and usually spent months from January to March in Stanford at the Hoover Institution, doing his research and collaborating there with his coauthor Barry R. Weingast.
  Folders are organized by date. For most of the early correspondence, there is one folder for each year. In later years, there is mostly one folder for each month. In later years North also titled some folders according to a particular subject or organization.
  - 1950 (Box 1)
    From John S. Richards to Dr. Raymond B. Allen, President of University of Washington. Research proposal from Morris David Morris, assistant professor at University of Michigan.
  - 1951 (Box 1)
    From James M. Davis Fulbright Advisor to Mr. David Wodlinger, Director of U.S. Student Program - request for a report on a candidate for fellowship.
  - 1954 (Box 1)
  - 1955 (Box 1)
  - 1956 (Box 1)
    Marcus E. Hobbs, Philip. W. Cartwright, Lloyd S. Woodburne, Morris David Morris with Ford Foundation and others.
  - 1957 (Box 1)
    Morris David Morris, J. Richard Huber, Marius B. Jansen and others.
  - 1958 (Box 1)
  - 1959 (Box 1)
  - 1960 (Box 1)
    Horace I. Poleman, Morris David Morris, J. Richard Huber.
  - 1961 (Box 1)
    Morris David Morris's economic seminar in India.
  - 1962 (Box 1)
  - 1963 (Box 1)
  - 1965 (Box 1)
  - 1966 (Box 1)
    J. B. Gillingham, Morris David Morris and Philip W. Cartwright.
  - 1967 (Box 1)
    Solomon Katz, Dr. C. Easton Rothwell and Morris David Morris.
  - 1968 (Box 1)
    From Douglass C. North to Morris David Morris.
  - 1970 (Box 1)
    Robert Fogel.
  - 1971 (Box 1)
    Robert Thomas, Douglass C. North, Emmanuel Le Roy Ladurie and others.
  - 1973 (Box 1)
    Douglass C. North, Priscilla Oakeshott and others.
  - 1974 (Box 1)
    Douglass C. North, Max Hartwell, Charles Feinstein and others.
  - 1978 (Box 1)
    Moses Abramovitz, Gerald Gunderson, Stanley E. Engerman and others.
  - 1979, Jan. - Sept. (Box 1)
    George Stigler, George Dalton and others.
  - 1979, Oct. - Dec. (Box 1)
    Robert Fogel, Lance Davis and others.
  - 1979 (Box 1)
    Stanley Lewis Engerman and Morris David Morris, about Guggenheim Memorial Foundation.
  - 1980 (1 of 3) (Box 1)
    Gaston V. Rimlinger, Lloyd Mercer, Lance Davis and others.
  - 1980 (2 of 3) (Box 1)
    Review for publishers - journals and others.
  - 1980 (3 of 3) (Box 1)
    Ernest M. Henley.
  - 1981 (Box 1)
    Richard Freeman, Richard Stuch, Charles R. Plott and others.
  - 1981-1982 (1 of 3) (Box 1)
    A. D. I. Nicol, A. B. Shone and others.
  - 1981-1982 (2 of 3) (Box 1)
    Bellagio applications.
  - 1981-1982 (3 of 3) (Box 1)
    Michael J. Lacey, Larry R. Cross and others.
  - 1982 (Box 1)
    John Baden, Richard A. Easterlin and others.
  - 1982 - 1983, 2 folders (Box 2)
    Journal of Political Economy. Referee reports.
  - 1983 (Box 2)
    Proposal by North with Henry Manne (Emory Univ.) for Sloan Grant for collaboration.
  - 1983 (Box 2)
    NBER.
  - 1983 Jan. - July (Box 2)
    David W. Galenson, Paul David and others.
  - 1983 Apr. (Box 2)
    Henry R. Luce Professorship. Ralph E. Morrow, Merle King and others.
  - 1983 Aug. - Sept. (Box 2)
    Eli Shapiro, Mark Blaug, Vernon Smith and others.
  - 1983 Oct. (Box 2)
    Samuel R. Gammon, Wilhelm Neuefeind and others.
  - 1983 Nov. (Box 2)
    Philip J. Cook, Robert C. Vogel and others.
  - 1983 Dec. (Box 2)
    Donald N. McCloskey, Kenneth Sokoloff, Reuven Brenner and others.
  - 1984 Jan. (Box 2)
    Donald N. McCloskey, Michael D. Bordo and others.
  - 1984 Feb. (Box 2)
    Simon Kuznets, Oliver E. Williamson and others.
  - 1984 Mar. (Box 2)
    Kerry Odell, Marcel Boyer and others.
  - 1984 Apr.-May and Aug. (Box 2)
    Robert W. Clower, Peter Evans and others.
  - 1984, Oct.-Nov. (Box 2)
    Kenneth Sokoloff.
  - 1985, Jan. (Box 2)
    Robert L. Virgil, Morton Rothstein and others.
  - 1985, Feb. (Box 2)
    Charles K. Rowley, Richard J. Sullivan and others.
  - 1985, Mar. (Box 3)
    Reuven Brenner, Clifford Geertz and others.
  - 1985, Apr. 4 (Box 3)
    Margaret Rouse Bates's CV.
  - 1985, Apr. (Box 3)
    Robert Brenner, Rudolf Richter and others.
  - 1985, May (Box 3)
    Johan Myhrman, Johnna Barto and others.
  - 1985, June (Box 3)
    Agmar Sandmo, Robert Bates and others.
  - 1985, July - Aug. (Box 3)
    Robert Bates, Farley Grubb and others.
  - 1985, Sept. (Box 3)
    Reuven Brenner, Yoram Barzel, Donald McCloskey and others.
  - 1985, Oct. (Box 3)
    Robert Keohane and others.
  - 1985, Nov. (Box 3)
    Robert Keohane, Rudolf Richter and others.
  - 1985, Dec. (Box 3)
    Reuven Brenner, David W. Galenson and others.
  - 1985, Dec. 5 (Box 3)
    Rudolf Richter
  - 1985 (Box 3)
    Herman Wold.
  - 1985 (Box 3)
    Institute for the History of Freedom.
  - 1986, Jan. (Box 3)
    Leonard F. Ralston, Annette Milford and others.
  - 1986, Feb. (Box 3)
    Dennis Mueller, Peter Gourevitch and others.
  - 1986, Mar. (Box 3)
    Terry Anderson, notes on Hayek's Constitution of Liberty (5 pp.) by Barry Weingast, Reuven Brenner and others.
  - 1986, Mar. 14 (Box 3)
    Jeffrey Blumberg.
  - 1986 Mar.-Aug. (Box 93)
    Ira A. Glazier, The Journal of European Economic History
  - 1986, Apr. (Box 3)
    Robert Virgil, Terry Anderson and others.
  - 1985, Dec. - 1986, Apr. (Box 4)
    NBER Board of Directors Meeting.
  - 1986 (Box 4)
    Terry Moe, Gary Miller and others.
  - 1986 (Box 4)
    Robert Lucas and others.
  - 1986 (Box 4)
    Martin Feldstein and others.
  - 1986, Aug. (Box 4)
    Gary Libecap, Gordon Tullok and others.
  - 1986, Sept. (Box 4)
    Vernon Smith, George Stigler, John Baden and others.
  - 1986, Oct. (Box 4)
    Alfred Chandler, Robert Higgs, Jules Coleman and others.
  - 1986, Nov. (Box 4)
    Margarete Levi and others.
  - 1986 (Box 4)
    TIAA/CREF Nomination.
  - 1986, Dec. (Box 4)
    Don McCloskey and others.
  - 1987, Jan. (Box 4)
    Paul David and others.
  - 1987, Feb. (Box 4)
    Paul Romer and others.
  - 1987, Mar. (Box 4)
    Brad De Long, Rachelle Hollander and others.
  - 1987, Apr. (Box 5)
    Vernon Smith, Robert Haveman, John Hughes and others.
  - 1987, May (Box 5)
    Paul David, Robert Haveman, Vernon Smith, T.N. Srinivasan and others.
  - 1987, June (Box 5)
    Ronald Coase, Paul David, T.N. Srinivasan and others.
  - 1987, July (Box 5)
    Donald McCloskey, Robert Keohane, Yoram Barzel and others.
  - 1987, Aug. (Box 5)
    Long letter to Robert Bates re: Coase Theorem; Ramon H. Myers, Gordon Tullok, Henry Manne and others.
  - 1987, Sept. (Box 5)
    Yoram Barzel, Robert Haveman, Warren Samuels and others.
  - 1987, Oct. (Box 5)
    Vernon Smith and others.
  - 1987, Nov. (Box 5)
  - 1987, Dec. (Box 5)
    Gordon Tullock, Daniel Bromley and others.
  - June 1987 - June 1988 (Box 5)
    Barry Weingast, Robert Fogel, Henry Manne and others.
  - 1988 (Box 5)
    David W. Galenson.
  - 1988, Jan. (Box 5)
    Jennifer Roback, Robert Virgil and others.
  - 1988, Feb. (Box 6)
    Mike Haupert, Dilip Mookherjee and others.
  - 1988, Mar. (Box 6)
    David Galenson, Rogers Hollingsworth and others.
  - , 1988, Apr. (Box 6)
    Herman Wold, Thrainn Eggertsson and others.
  - 1988, May (Box 6)
    Robert Higgs, Vernon Smith and others.
  - 1988, June (Box 6)
    Correspondence re: Hong Kong exams.
  - 1988, July (Box 6)
    Samuel Bowles, John Sullivan, Robert Fogel, Oliver E Williamson, Barry Weingast and others.
  - 1988, Aug. (Box 6)
    John Sullivan, Barry Weingast, George Stigler.
  - 1988, Aug. (Box 6)
    Thomas Kuczynski, Masato Nakajima and others.
  - 1988, Oct. (Box 6)
    Robert Richter, Perry Shapiro, Kenneth A. Shepsle, Cynthia Taft Morris and others.
  - 1988, Nov. (Box 6)
    Elinor Ostrom, David A. Baldwin and others.
  - 1988, Dec. (Box 6)
    Rudolf Richter, Arthur Denzau and others.
  - 1988 (1 of 2) (Box 6)
    Political Economy Center.
  - 1988 (2 of 2) (Box 6)
    History of Freedom, faculty recruitment.
  - 1989, Jan. (Box 6)
    Bo Gustafsson, Robert Fogel, Jerry Jenkins, Oliver E. Williamson and others.
  - 1989, Feb. (Box 6)
    Barry Schwartz, Horst Claus Recktenwald, Gary Becker, George Stigler, Karen Cook, Oliver Williamson and others.
  - 1989, Mar. (1 of 2) (Box 6)
    Wallis - NSF request.
  - 1989, Mar. (2 of 2) (Box 7)
    Joseph Stiglitz, Gary Becker and others.
  - 1989, Apr. (Box 7)
    Barry Weingast, Pablo Spiller and others.
  - 1989, May (Box 7)
    David Friedman, Michael L. Boyd and others.
  - 1989, June (Box 7)
    John C. H. Fei, Ted Walther and others.
  - 1989, July (Box 7)
    Ted Walther, Peter Huang and others.
  - 1989, Aug. (Box 7)
    Rudolf Richter, William H. Danforth and others.
  - 1989, Sept. (Box 7)
    Bruce Caldwell, Stanley L. Engerman, Robert Barro and others.
  - 1989, Oct. (Box 7)
    Jagdish Bhagwati, Gerald Jaynes and others.
  - 1989, Nov. (Box 7)
    Robert E. Gallman, Kenneth Sokoloff, Robert Brenner and others.
  - 1989, Dec. (Box 7)
    Jagdish Bhagwati, Peter Reill and others.
  - 1990, Jan. (Box 7)
    Phillip Keefer, Yoram Barzel and others.
  - 1990, Feb. (Box 7)
    Viktor Vanberg, Ramon H. Myers and others.
  - 1990, Mar. (Box 7)
    Robert H. Haveman, Gerald M. Meier and others.
  - 1990, Apr. (Box 8)
    Vinaod Thomas, W. Brian Arthur and others.
  - 1990, May (Box 8)
    Vinod Thomas, James A. Caporaso and others.
  - 1990, June (Box 8)
    Sharon L. Hotl, Jeffrey C. Alexander and others.
  - 1990, July (Box 8)
    John W. Barchfield, W. Brian Arthur and others.
  - 1990, Aug. (Box 8)
    Olympia Kaminioti, Steven N. S. Cheung and others.
  - 1990, Sept. (Box 8)
    Avner Greif, Albin Salton and others.
  - 1990, Oct. (Box 8)
    Vinod Thomas, T. N. Srinivasan and others.
  - 1990, Nov. (Box 8)
    David C. Wheelock, Barry Weingast and others.
  - 1990, Dec. (Box 8)
    Richard Rosset, David Plotke and others.
  - 1991, Jan. (Box 8)
    Pablo T. Spiller, Elinor Ostrom and others.
  - 1991, Feb. (Box 9)
    Vernon W. Ruttan, Morris David Morris and others.
  - 1991, Mar. (Box 9)
    Richard C. Rockwell, David Galenson and others.
  - 1991, Apr. (Box 9)
    Roger D. Congleton, James Buchanan and others.
  - 1991, May (Box 9)
    Vinod Thomas, David W. Galenson, Vernon Smith and others.
  - 1991, June (Box 9)
    Susanna Landesberg, Wilhelm Neufeind and others.
  - 1991, July (Box 9)
    Paul R. Milgrom, Robert Haveman and others.
  - 1991, Aug. (Box 9)
    Vera Draack, Sven-Erik Sjostrand and others.
  - 1991, Sept. (Box 9)
    Axel Leijonhufvud, Kenneth A. Shepsle and others.
  - 1991, Oct. (Box 9)
    William Zame, Robert Z. Aliber and others.
  - 1991, Nov. (Box 9)
    Thrainn Eggertsson, Oliver E. Williamson and others.
  - 1991, Dec. (Box 9)
    Martin H. Israel, Yoram Barzel and others.
  - 1992, Jan. (Box 10)
    Robert W. Fogel, Thomas E. Borcherding and others.
  - 1992, Feb. (Box 10)
    Avner Greif, Robert D. Putnam and others.
  - 1992, Mar. (1 of 2) (Box 10)
    Ron Stanfield, Masahiko Aoki and others.
  - 1992, Mar. (2 of 2) (Box 10)
    Martin Bronfenbrenner, Al Chandler and others.
  - 1992, Apr. (Box 10)
    Wilhelm Neuefeind, Alexandra Casella and others.
  - 1992, May (Box 10)
    Dennis C. Mueller, Marc de Vor and others.
  - 1992, June (Box 10)
    Robert L. Virgil, Dennis Ahlburgh and others.
  - 1992, July (Box 10)
    Pamela Evans, Richard Bensel and others.
  - 1992, Aug. (Box 11)
    Vernon W. Ruttan, Valentin Vasquez de Prada and others.
  - 1992, Sept. (Box 11)
    Graeme Snooks, Michael J. Haupert and others.
  - 1992, Oct. (Box 11)
    Martin J. Bailey, John B. Van Huyck and others.
  - 1992, Nov. (Box 11)
    Robert W. Fogel, Janet L. Craswell and others.
  - 1992, Dec. (Box 11)
    John Sprague, Colin Day and others.
  - 1993, Jan. (Box 11)
    Jay B. Barney, John Sprague and others.
  - 1993, Feb. (Box 11)
    Ramon H. Myers, James Alt and others.
  - 1993, Mar. (Box 11)
    Robert Higgs, W. Brian Arthur and others.
  - 1993, Apr. (Box 11)
    Louis P. Cain, Howard Stein and others.
  - 1993, May (Box 11)
    John Jat TePaske, Dennis O. Flynn and others.
  - 1993, May - 1994, Mar. (Box 11)
    Nobel Prize.
  - 1993, June (Box 11)
    Randall L. Calvert, Bruce Bueno de Mesquita and others.
  - 1993, July (Box 11)
    Carlos Poni, Randall L. Calvert and others.
  - 1993, Aug. (Box 12)
    Tim Yeager, John J. Moore and others.
  - 1993, Sept. (Box 12)
    Robert L. Byrd, Robert Higgs and others.
  - 1993, Oct. (1 of 2) (Box 12)
    Christopher I. Byrnes, Lynn R. Giardina and others.
  - 1993, Oct. (2 of 2) (Box 12)
    Oliver E. Williamson, John Lyons and others.
  - 1993, Nov. (Box 12)
    H. S. Gordon, Elyce Rotella and others.
  - 1993, Dec. (Box 12)
    Aldo De Maddalena, Bo Gustafsson and others.
  - 1994, Jan. (1 of 2) (Box 12)
    Stanley L. Engerman, Amartya Sen and others.
  - 1994, Jan. (2 of 2) (Box 12)
    D. A. Livesey, Colin M. Lewis and others.
  - 1994, Feb. (Box 13)
    A. W. Coats, Peggy Sue Heath and others.
  - 1994, Mar. (1 of 2) (Box 13)
    Alberto de Capitani, William C. Dunkelberg and others.
  - 1994, Mar. (2 of 2) (Box 13)
    Avner Greif, Thomas K. Rymes and others.
  - 1994, Apr. (1 of 2) (Box 13)
    Carlo Poni, Elizabeth Dickhouse and others.
  - 1994, Apr. (2 of 2) (Box 13)
    Alberto de Capitani, Gabriel Tortella and others.
  - 1994, May (Box 13)
    Michael Watts, Brian Levy and others.
  - 1994, June (Box 14)
    Terry Hogley, Tom Mayer and others.
  - 1994, July (Box 14)
    Yasuo Suzuki, Antonio Escudero and others.
  - 1994, Aug. (Box 14)
    Paul Jensen, Michael Page and others.
  - 1994, Sept. (Box 14)
    Avinash K. Dixit, Avner Greif and others.
  - 1994, Oct. (Box 14)
    Correspondence re: path dependency workshop at Columbia University and others.
  - 1994, Nov. (Box 14)
    Eirik Furubotn, Neil De Marchi
  - 1994, Dec. (Box 14)
    Roger Myerson, Oliver E. Myerson and others.
  - 1995, Jan. (Box 15)
    Oliver E. Williamson and others.
  - 1995, Feb. (Box 15)
    James Alt, Elias L. Khalil and others.
  - 1995, Mar. (1 of 2) (Box 15)
    Ronald Coase, Avner Ben-Ner, Brian Arthur, Lawrence Klein and others.
  - 1995, Mar. (2 of 2) (Box 15)
    Economic Transition Group.
  - 1995, Apr. (Box 15)
    Claude Menard and others.
  - 1995, May (Box 15)
    Elias L. Khalil, Pavel Pelikan and others.
  - 1995, June (Box 15)
    Carlos Bernanrdez, Avinash Dixit and others.
  - 1995, July (Box 15)
    Barry Eichengreen, Julio Dittborn and Pete Wenzel.
  - 1995, Aug. (Box 15)
    Kate Burrel, Nathaniel H. Leff and others.
  - 1995, Sept. (Box 15)
    Gary Libecap, Paul B. Trescott and others.
  - 1995, Oct. (Box 16)
    Manuel Castells, Michael Keren and others.
  - 1995, Nov. (Box 16)
    Byoungki Lee, Alejandro Hernandez and others.
  - 1995, Dec. (Box 16)
    Bob Bates, Timur Kuran and others.
  - 1996, Jan. (Box 16)
    Barry Boyer, Yoong-Deok Jeon and others.
  - 1996, Feb. (Box 16)
    Douglass C. North to his secretary.
  - 1996, Mar. (Box 16)
    James K. Weeks and Peter Bernholz.
  - 1996, Apr. (Box 16)
    Michael K. Salemi and Barbara Burgess.
  - 1996, May (Box 16)
    Julio Dittborn, Anne Hetlage and others.
  - 1996, June (Box 16)
    Michael D. Intriligator, Susan E. Garfield and others.
  - 1996, July (Box 16)
    Manfred E. Streit, Bozhong Li and others.
  - 1996, Aug. (Box 16)
    Lorena Alcazar and Gunnar Eliasson (fax cover pages only).
  - 1996, Sept. (Box 16)
    Richard Nelson, Avinash Dixit and others.
  - 1996, Oct. (Box 16)
    Dali L. Yang, Bill Eskridge and others.
  - 1996, Nov. (Box 16)
    Microsoft, The Royal Swedish Academy of Science and others.
  - 1996, Nov. - 1997, Oct. (Box 16)
    Widener University
  - 1996, Dec. (Box 16)
    Robert A Scott, Judith Rodin and others.